openstudy.com 2015-12-18

# OpenStudy: Study Together

##### Forgot Your Password?

  * About Us
  * Partner With Us
  * Press
  * Terms
  * Privacy
  * Code of Conduct
  * Teachers
  * What's New

**Privacy Policy – Revised October 2015**

  1. **Introduction**

This Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") describes how OpenStudy, Inc. ("OpenStudy") collects, uses and discloses information from and about visitors to and users of OpenStudy.com, including unregistered visitors ("Visitors"), registered subscription members ("Members") and registered non-subscription guests ("Guests"), as each category is further described in the Terms of Use, and what choices Members, Guests and Visitors each have regarding the collection and use of such information. This Privacy Policy also explains procedures for the security and protection of the information collected and how you can access and update your information. 

By registering with the OpenStudy.com web site ("Web Site") or by using any of the OpenStudy products or services as a Member or Guest, or by accessing the Web Site as a Visitor, you agree to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy, including OpenStudy’s policies with respect to the collection, use and disclosure of personal and non-personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. 

  2. **Information Collected**

Open Study collects and stores certain personally identifiable information about you when you provide it to us during registration (or when you update your account information), when you use or subscribe to Open Study’s products and services, including when you respond to Open Study’s surveys or submit content or materials to Open Study, or when you otherwise communicate with Open Study, such as through emails. The type of personally identifiable information collected may include your name, address, email address, telephone number, credit card information, school, demographic information, and other personal information, depending upon the particular Open Study product or service, the information requested and provided and the category of user. 

For example, a user, as part of the registration process, will provide OpenStudy with the necessary and correct information to properly collect payment or dues for the use of the OpenStudy services. Certain information requested by OpenStudy during the registration process is optional, including providing demographic information, and for Visitors who may wish to participate in surveys, the requested personal information is optional. For a Visitor wishing to receive the monthly OpenStudy newsletter, only a valid email address is required. 

OpenStudy also collects and stores certain non-personally identifiable information about you when you visit and use the Web Site or otherwise interact with OpenStudy, including using OpenStudy's products and services, submitting content or materials to OpenStudy and responding to surveys and email communications. The type of non-personal information collected may include your computer and internet connection information, including IP address and operating system, and your usage history of the Web Site and its web pages. 

This non-personal information may be gathered by using "cookies" and/or "clear GIF" (Graphical Interchange Format) technologies, as well as login file information. "Cookies" are small data files with a unique identifier that we transfer to your computer's hard drive or web browser and that collect and store data about your visit to the Web Site. This allows our systems to identify you when you return to the Web Site and to analyze your Web Site usage. "GIFs" are small graphic files with a unique identifier contained in our Web Site that we use to track Web Site traffic. This allows us to monitor and improve the performance of the Web Site and the related services offered and to collect and use the information as described in this Privacy Policy. This non-personally identifiable information will be treated in the same fashion, and in aggregate to, all information provided by a Member, Guest or Visitor. 

  3. **Use of Information**

OpenStudy uses your personal and non-personal information in order to improve and personalize your use of the Web Site and its related products and services, including by tracking and monitoring traffic on the Web Site so as to enhance the performance of the Web Site and to customize your online research. 

OpenStudy generally does not share your personal information with third parties, except to the extent necessary to process transactions with you, for example, credit card processing companies or in the case of contests that include a third party partner, or promotional offers. However, Open Study may disclose any such information pursuant to law, including subpoena, warrants or other orders; in order to enforce the Terms of Use or other Web Site policies and rules with respect to a particular OpenStudy product or service including reporting suspected cheating or intellectual property rights violations to your academic institution or others who have a need to know of such activity, or any other related agreements between you and OpenStudy; or as otherwise may be required to protect the rights of OpenStudy, its directors, officers, representatives and agents, or its Members, Guests or Visitors. 

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, click here ([www.networkadvertising.org](http://networkadvertising.org/)). 

In addition, OpenStudy may share some or all of your personal information with another entity in the event of a change in business structure, including merger or acquisition, as well as with the representatives of the entity to the extent required. 

Except as described above, OpenStudy will not disclose any personal information about you to third parties without your permission. 

We may share aggregated demographic information about our user base with our partners. This information does not identify individual users. 

As a user or guest, you may access and update your personal information as described in the Terms of Use, however, information originally submitted to OpenStudy by you may be retained by OpenStudy for technical, legal or other reasons. 

  4. **General Limitations**

This Privacy Policy is part of the Terms of Use. OpenStudy may revise or amend this Privacy Policy from time to time, and it is your responsibility to regularly review this Privacy Policy for any changes to it. If you have any questions or concerns about privacy at OpenStudy or about this Privacy Policy, please contact us by email at contact@openstudy.com or in writing to OpenStudy, Inc. 

OpenStudy implements reasonable steps to maintain the privacy and security of your information against unauthorized access consistent with industry standards, however, as with all online transactions, "hackers" or other third parties may intercept and misuse your personal information, including during transmission to and from the Web Site. 

The Web Site and its related products and services are not intended for use by children under 13 years of age and children under 13 may not submit personal information to OpenStudy. OpenStudy will not knowingly collect or use personal information of anyone under 13 years of age, and if OpenStudy is informed or determines that any such information has been submitted, it will be deleted. 

**I am over 13 years of age, and agree to the Terms of Use and understand the Privacy Policy.**
